guideline.com 2015-11-10

# Privacy - ORC International, Inc.

**Regional Policies**

View [ **Australia Privacy Policy**](http://orcinternational.com/australia-privacy-policy/)

View **[UK Terms of Use](http://orcinternational.co.uk/uk-terms-of-use/)**

View **[UK Quality Policy](http://orcinternational.co.uk/quality-policy/)**

**Online Services**

View: **[Online Services Terms and Conditions](http://orcinternational.co.uk/online-terms-and-conditions/)**

**ORC International Privacy Policy**

**Scope**

This ORC International (ORC) Online Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by ORC International through any of its websites which display or link to this policy. It does not apply to those ORC International Websites, services and products which either do not display or link to this statement or have their own privacy statements. ORC International is not responsible for the data policies, procedures or content of any third party website which may be linked from this website. ORC International, a global market research firm, is committed to maintaining the privacy and security of your personal information according to the terms outlined in this Policy. As a founding member of the Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO) and member of the European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research (ESOMAR), we must adhere to rigorous industry standards which exist in part to safeguard your privacy and the security of your personal information. This website is not used to collect information from survey participants.

**Information We Collect and How We Use It**

We do not collect personally identifying information at this site from users unless it is provided to us knowingly and voluntarily. In certain parts of the site, you may communicate with us via an online form and/or by e-mail. Through these channels, you may disclose limited personal information to us, such as your name, title, street address, company, telephone/fax numbers, email address and certain other information which will enable us to respond to your inquiries about our expertise, products, services, career opportunities, etc. and/or to your request to receive periodic communications from us. When you voluntarily submit personal information via this website for any of these purposes, we will use the personal information you provide in accordance with the purpose for which it was submitted. Though you are under no obligation to provide us with this information, withholding it may prevent us from responding to your inquiry. When you provide any personal information to us through this website, you acknowledge that you are knowingly and voluntarily consenting to its use as described in this Privacy Policy.

**Cookies and Usage Tracking Information**

Like many companies, we use “cookie” technology on our site. The cookies we use do not collect any personally identifying information about you or provide us with any way to contact you, nor do they extract any unrelated information about your computer. These cookies may tell us whether you are a new or previous visitor, as well as what material you have viewed. We also collect certain usage information about our site, such as the number and frequency of visitors to its various sections, which may be used for the general purpose of improving our website. Collected data is used only in the aggregate and does not include any personally identifying information.

**Use of Personal Information by Third Parties**

Except as stated in this Policy, ORC International does not disclose the personally identifying information collected on this website to any person or entity controlling, controlled by, or under common control with ORC International. We occasionally hire other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, such as handling the processing and delivery of mailings, providing customer support, hosting websites, processing transactions, or performing statistical analysis of our services. Those companies will be permitted to obtain only the personal information they need to deliver the service; are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information; and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose. ORC International may disclose personally identifying information collected on this website if we believe such action is required by law or desirable to permit us to exercise our legal rights or take action regarding illegal activities, or if we have a good faith belief that you are in violation of the terms of service. Should there be a change in control of ORC International or all or part of the company is sold, merged, or otherwise transferred to another entity, we may transfer personally identifying information as part of that transaction.

**Security**

We take reasonable technical and organizational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. However, as information transmission over the internet is inherently insecure, we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the internet.

**Safe Harbor Certification**

ORC International adheres to the US-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the US-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from EU member countries and Switzerland. ORC International has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view ORC International’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor>.

**Contact Us**

Questions regarding this Policy and related privacy issues should be directed to ORC International by sending an e-mail with the subject line “privacy,” along with a thorough description of your concern.

**Conditions of Use and Your Consent**

When you use this site, you consent to the transmission of personally identifying information and to its use as described herein. As this website may be hosted outside your geographic region, any email communications or communications you send us through this website may be directed to a server that is not located within your home country. Regardless of your geographic location, use of our website and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Policy and to the laws of the state of New Jersey, where applicable.

**Changes to This Online Privacy Policy**

If we make a material change to this policy or to our privacy practices, we will post an updated Policy either at this location or elsewhere on our website in a prominent location. The updated Policy will reflect the date of the last revision.
